A Guide to the Fielding Dawson Papers 1978.0003
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Letters to Mother, 1949-1953
    - Letters to mother, 1953 (Box 16)
  - Letters from Mother, 1953-1983
    - Letters from mother, 1953-1968 (Box 16)
    - Letters from mother, 1953-1968 (Box 16)
    - Letters from mother, 1969-1972 (Box 16)
    - Letters from mother, 1969-1972 (Box 16)
    - Letters from mother, 1969-1972 (Box 16)
    - Letters from mother, 1969-1972 (Box 16)
    - Letters from mother, 1969-1972 (Box 16)
    - Letters from mother, 1969-1972 (Box 16)
    - Letters from mother, 1973-1975 (Box 16)
    - Letters from mother, 1973-1975 (Box 16)
    - Letters from mother, 1973-1975 (Box 16)
    - Letters from mother, 1973-1975 (Box 16)
    - Letters from mother, 1973-1975 (Box 16)
    - Letters from mother, 1973-1975 (Box 16)
    - Letters from mother, 1973-1975 (Box 16)
  - Letters from Family and Childhood Friends
    - Dawson, Cara, 1965-1978 (Box 17)
    - Dawson, Cara, 1979-1980 (Box 17)
    - Dawson, Cara, 1981-1982 (Box 17)
    - Dawson, Cara, 1983 (Box 17)
    - Letters from childhood friends (Box 17)
    - Letters from Barbara Dawson (ex-wife), 1975-1977 (Box 17)
    - Letters from Aunts and Uncles, ca. 1960s-1970s (Box 17)
    - Letters from sister, ca. 1970s (Box 17)
    - Letters from James Dawson (brother?), 1974-1977 (Box 17)
    - Letters from James Dawson (brother?), 1974-1977 (Box 17)
    - Letters from James Dawson (brother?), 1974-1977 (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous Letters
    - Author Unknown (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous Items (Box 17)
    - Correspondence with editors, publishers, etc. Re: Dawson's writings (Box 18)
    - Recommendation Letters by Dawson (Box 18)
    - Dawson Miscellaneous Letters (Box 18)
- Series III. Works of Others
  Series III, WORKS OF OTHERS, contains various writings saved by Dawson. There are two divisions: newspaper articles and reviews of Dawson by others, and books, poems, etc. by others. The first division is arranged according to the title of Dawson's work. The second division is arranged alphabetically according to the last name of the writer. Some of the poems and other works were written by people that Dawson knew personally.
  - Newspaper Articles and Reviews of Dawson by Others
    - A Great Day for a Ballgame (Review) (Box 18)
    - An Essay on New American Fiction (Review) - p.290 (Box 18)
    - The Dream/Thunder Road (Review) (Box 18)
    - Emotional Memoir (Review) (Box 18)
    - Gafford, Charlotte on Dawson (Box 18)
    - The Greatest Story Ever Told (Review) (Box 18)
    - Krazy Kat (Review) (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous News Articles on Dawson (Box 18)
    - Newspaper Reviews - Mandalay Dream (Review) (Box 18)
    - Open Road (Review) (Box 18)
  - Books, Poems, etc. by Others
    - Blackwood, Algernon (Box 18)
    - Cohen, Judith (Box 18)
    - The Gold Diggers and Other Stories, Robert Creeley (Box 18)
    - Daley, John (Box 18)
    - Davies, Alan (Box 18)
    - The Sensuous Dork, by James G. Dawson (Box 18)
    - Eshelman, Clayton (Box 18)
    - Hallberg, Bill (Box 18)
    - Hellenberg, Lorin & Larry (Box 18)
    - Henderson, J. (Box 18)
    - Honey, William C. (Box 18)
    - Huddleston (Box 18)
    - Her Fatal Mistake, by Lewis, E. Francis (Box 18)
    - Marcille, N. (Box 18)
    - Micheleni, Jack (Box 18)
    - Newman, Robert (Box 18)
    - Oravec, Kerry (Box 18)
    - Rodstein, Miriam (Box 18)
    - Scroggy (Box 18)
    - Schliffer, Marion (Box 18)
    - Splendide-Hotel, Gilbert Sorrentino (Box 18)
    - Stark, Brad (Box 18)
    - Tail light (Box 18)
    - Wade, Mary Lizz Ittner (Box 18)
    - Hammer me Home, Richard R. Werry (Box 18)
    - Collection of Writings Selected for Reprinting (in Neon) (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material By Others (Box 18)
    - Unidentifiable Works of Others (Box 18)
    - Originals Artworks (Box 18)
- Series IV. Photos, Artwork, and Memorabilia
  Series IV, PHOTOS, ARTWORK, AND MEMORABILIA, is composed of various non-literary records pertaining to Dawson's life. Seven divisions have been created: assorted photos, artwork, slides and tape recordings, Black Mountain and Franz Kline memorabilia, calendars and diaries, financial and legal records, and personal memorabilia.
  - Assorted Photos
    - Germany, Paris, 1955 (Box 19)
    - Mexico, Nantucket (Box 19)
    - Kirkwood, 1950s, 1960s (Box 19)
    - Assorted Photos 1 (Box 19)
    - Assorted Photos 2 (Box 19)
    - Self-photos (Box 19)
    - Kline, et. al (Box 19)
    - Photo (Box 19)
    - Photographs, ca. 1960-1970 (Box 19)
    - Larry Funk Photos (Box 19)
    - Hurst Photos (Box 19)
    - Scrabook (Dismantled): original order retained in 2 boxes (Box 1 of 2) (Box 19a)
    - Scrabook (Dismantled): original order retained in 2 boxes (Box 2 of 2) (Box 19b)
  - Artwork
    - Artwork (Box 20)
    - Envelope Drawing, man with beard in pencil to green ink (Box 20)
    - Dawson Portrait of Olson (Box 20)
    - Sketches (unsorted), ca. 1946-1970 (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous Artwork (Box 20)
  - Slides and Tape Recordings
    - Tape Recording at Kent State (Box 20)
    - Tape Recording: NYC, Mexico (Box 20)
    - Slides (Box 20)
  - Black Mountain and Franz Kline Memorabilia
    - Black Mountain Material (Box 20)
    - Black Mountain Materials (Box 20)
    - Interview with Fielding Dawson (2 Copies) (Box 20)
    - BMC bulletin, Cage et al., Summer 1952 (Box 20)
    - Chamber Music Concert flyer, recital by David Tudor, August 3, 1953 (Box 20)
    - Blood Wedding offset flyer, BMC, December 12, 1952 (Box 20)
    - 3 postcards, BMC showing murals inspired by Jean Charlot, 1944 (Box 20)
    - BMC Bulletin 5: Work with Materials by Anni Albers (Box 20)
    - Letter from Fielding Dawson to Mrs. C.H. Dawson (Poetess), January 24, 1956 (Box 20)
    - Letter from Fielding Dawson to Mrs. C.H. Dawson, January 9, 1953 (Box 20)
    - BMC Poster, Orange lettering on blue background, Summer 1954 (Box 20)
    - BMC brochure with photos, ca. 1950 (Box 20)
    - 2 & 4 Poems by Jack Boyd & Dawson, ed. of 250, August 1950 (Box 20)
    - Recital by David Tudor of Contemporary Music, flyer, August 19, No Year (Box 20)
    - Letter from Fielding Dawson to Robert Creeley, typed on graph paper, double-sided, May 6, 1955 (Box 20)
    - Abstract Drawing, pencil on paper (Box 20)
    - Franz Kline Memorabilia (Box 20)
  - Calendars and Diaries
    - Calendars/Diaries (Box 20)
    - Calendars/Diaries (Box 20)
    - Calendars/Diaries (Box 20)
    - Calendars/Diaries (Box 20)
  - Financial and Legal Records
    - Financial & Legal (Box 20)
  - Personal Memorabilia (Box 21)
- Series V. Assorted Publications
  Series V, ASSORTED PUBLICATIONS, is comprised of a number of printed writings, none of which are authored by Dawson. Two divisions are present: art and literary announcements (some of which refer to works of Dawson), and various periodicals, magazines, etc.
  - Art and Literary Announcements
    - Literary Announcements concerning Dawson (Box 22)
    - Art/Music Announcements (Box 22)
    - Literary Announcements (Box 22)
  - Various Periodicals, Magazines, Etc.
    - Authors Guild Bulletin (Box 22)
    - Kirkwood Historical Review (Box 22)
    - Kirkwood Historical Review (Box 22)
    - American Journal (Box 22)
    - North American Review (Box 22)
    - New York Mets Programs (Box 22)
    - 200 Years of American Painting (Box 22)
    - Assorted Magazines (Box 22)
    - Assorted Magazines (Box 22)
    - Newspaper Articles (Box 22)
    - Assorted Newspapers (Box 22)
    - Newspaper Containing Letter by Jim Dawson (Box 22)
    - Catalogs (Box 22)
    - Articles (Box 22)